

Andrej Gajdos

Software Engineer / Full-Stack Web Developer







I am a software engineer, consultant and tech blogger with over six years of experience delivering software. I have worked for clients all around the world in many different industries. A background in computer science and my ability as a full-stack developer allow me to create everything from small business websites to custom web applications.

https://andrejgajdos.com

@mail@andrejgajdos.com

Experience

August 2017

- Present

Freelance Software Engineer, Consultant

- Consult with clients to determine user needs and design solutions.
- Complete wide range of software development and programming tasks on contract basis.
- Development web applications primarily in JavaScript, Node.js, React.js.
- I joined Toptal's network to be able to work on interesting projects. Toptal is an exclusive network of the top 3% freelance software developers, designers, and finance experts in the world.

July 2018 – May 2019

React Developer (contractor), Nash

- Built company's fully responsive website.
- Built customisable UI components used across multiple projects.
- Built functional prototype of funds management and payments system in exchange platform.
- Technologies: Javascript, React, Gatsby, styled-components, Typescript.

August 2017 – May 2018

Principal Software Engineer (contractor), SayCaster (rebranded to Bitcast)

- Designed and built an interactive podcast platform. Podcasters can upload audio files and add "spots" to specific moments in their podcasts, which can be anything from links, to social media posts, to other videos or images. Listeners are engaged with content, such as social media posts or preview of external web pages.
- Built a single-page app from scratch with a complex user interface, including user interactions and animations.
- Designed and developed a RESTful API server.
- o Technologies: Heroku, Amazon S3, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, Node.js, Koa, Objection.js, Knex.js, React.js, Redux, D3.js, SVG, Webpack, Babel, Twitter API, InVision.

June 2016 – July 2017

Pre-sales Engineer, ZeroTurnaround

- Presented and demonstrated products to potential customers from all over the world.
- Demonstrated product features to developer teams and showed how to use them in the development process with a specific workflow, environment, and toolset.
- Helped sales associates close deals by presenting our products in specific use-cases.
- Trained sales associates in how to effectively present and sell our tools to developer teams and managers.
- Assisted customers with installation, troubleshooting, and other customer service for configuration issues.

April 2015 - June 2015

Software Engineer, Ataccama

- o Implemented new features and fixed bugs in enterprise applications used for data quality management, rewrote UI components to modern technologies.
- Designed and implemented the front-end of interactive application for customer data management.
- Designed and implemented server-to-sever communication and server push in GWT application.
- Technologies: Java, JavaScript, ES6, React.js, Flux, Immutable.js, Backbone, jQuery, Bootstrap, SCSS, Webpack, Gulp, Babel, D3.js, JSP, JSTL, JMS, ActiveMQ and Errai.

July 2013

- December 2013; September 2014

- April 2015

Java Developer, Taranzo, Techniserv

- Analysed, designed and implemented solutions for gathering and processing structured and unstructured data from social networks and various other sources.
- Designed and implemented a module for building and visualisation of social network used by security forces to detect criminal activity.
- o Technologies: Java, JavaScript, Liferay, Spring MVC, Maven, JSP, JSTL, jQuery, Bootstrap, D3.js, Jung, OrientDB, YouTube and Twitter API's.

July 2012 - June 2013

Software Tester, Amberg Engineering

- Responsible for execution and result analysis of both manual and automated tests.
- Developed and maintained whole test infrastructure with automated tests.
- Designed test cases, wrote documentation, and reported issues.
- Technologies: JavaScript, Python, Ruby languages and Squish tool.

Education

February 2013

- June 2015

Master's degree in Service Science, Management and Engineering

Faculty of Informatics, Masaryk University

Master's thesis: User interface for analysis of personal relationships in unstructured data

January 2014

- July 2014

Master's degree (Erasmus exchange student) in Innovation and Research in Informatics

Barcelona School of Informatics, Polytechnic University of Catalonia

September 2009

- February 2013

Bachelor's degree in Applied Informatics

Faculty of Informatics, Masaryk University

Bachelor's thesis: Testing of graphical user interfaces

Last projects

Nash

- Blazing fast static website built with React and Gatsby.
- All pages are fully responsive and optimised for mobile viewing.
- Technologies: React, Gatsby, Styled-components, Typescript.

to Bitcast)

- Saycaster (rebranded o A podcast platform where podcasters can upload audio files and add 'spots' to specific moments in their podcasts.
 - Podcasters can add anything from links, to social media posts, to other videos or images.
 - Listeners are engaged with content, such as social media posts or preview of external web pages.
 - I developed a RESTful API and built a single-page app from scratch.
 - o Technologies: Node.js, PostgreSQL, Heroku, React, Redux, D3.js.

<u>FastSwims</u>

• Event management platform for managing swimming teams and swimming competitions.

- I designed a new user interface based on customer's prototypes and built a functional prototype.
- o Technologies: JavaScript, React, Redux.

Talks and presentations

February 2016

How to use React.js

<u>Webtlak</u> - <u>video</u> - <u>slides</u>

• Presentation about React.js, Flux pattern, ES6 and related libraries.